I'll look through
the window first.
And if the coast
is clear, I'll knock.
If it isn't, then I'll stop
being obsessed with him. Okay?
[WOMAN] I finished changing.
[GASPS]
- What is it?
- Girl--
You shouldn't waste
your tears on that guy.
There's nothing
wrong with you.
They're in the wrong
for leaving you.
For abandoning you.
And I'm just like them.
I think Jaja was really hurt
by what that person did.
Of course, she was, man.
What if someone
left you hanging
and started dating
someone else?
Ouch!
All I'm saying is, man...
We should help her move on.
Wa-Wait, hold on!
Wait, Emma, erase that!
- Why should I?
- What? Why?
It doesn't look good.
Seriously? You also
don't think I look good?
Jaja, I didn't mean you.
It's your clothes.
Could you please not judge me?
I need this.
My followers need
to see that I'm okay
and I'm not depressed.
Because right now?
I feel like
I'm such an ugly person.
I just need some...
just a bit of affirmation
that I'm still beautiful.
That I'm not
that easy to replace.
Jaja, you are irreplaceable.
If someone sees you as such,
then they're blind.
Because they don't see
your true worth.
[ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[ROMANTIC MUSIC FADES]
Wilberto... Wilberto...
Girl, his name is so common.
There are so many
search results!
- [TAPPING ON TABLET]
- Wilberto... De Guzman...
World War Two, Philippines.
Hmm... What if...
Why don't we
add Nadia's name
so we can narrow it down?
- Great idea.
- Alright.
- Nadia...
- ...Cruz.
Hm...
Find anything?
[UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING]
"Nadia Cruz won't talk about
her brother who abandoned her
during the war."
Uh...
[UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
"Her brother is the brave,
but forgotten hero
from Quezon Province,
Wilberto de Guzman.
Wilberto joined
the guerilla fighters
to fight off the invaders."
[DEEP, NERVOUS BREATHS]
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Son, never forget what you
promised your mother and I.
Never leave your sister
whatever happens.
Yes, Papa. I promise.
Hide yourselves.
Hide now!
- [SCREAMING]
- [BLOW LANDS]
[SCREAMING]
[GUNSHOTS]
- [GUNSHOTS]
- [DISTANT SCREAMS]
[SNIFFLES]
- Nadia?
- [SNIFFLES]
Don't cry, okay?
I will never leave you.
I promise you that, okay?
[JAJA] "But to Nadia,
that old wound is still fresh.
"A true hero would
have never left behind
the last of his family,
especially in the midst
of tragedy," Nadia added.
- [GUNSHOT]
- [DISTANT SCREAM]
[MELANCHOLIC MUSIC PLAYING]
The two of us
were the last ones, man.
I tried to protect her.
As much as I could.
I even joined
the guerrilla fighters
to help drive away
the invaders
and end the war.
That way, I could
give her a decent life.
But while that happened,
I became very strict with her.
That was probably why
she got so angry with me.
That was the last thing
we argued about.
After that...
I never got to return.
[MELANCHOLIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
[JAJA] "Unfortunately, like our
other brave heroes...
It's as if Wilberto de Guzman
was erased from our history.
There barely exists any
records about his heroism,
about how he defended a small
town until his dying breath."
[SIGHS] Wow.
Gosh, girl.
Turns out, Wilberto's a hero.
Awesome! At least we're
friends with a hero, right?
Although, an obscure one
that no one knows about.
Maybe that's why his sister
is so angry with him.
She probably thought
he abandoned her.
But what if he really did?
I mean, we've had heroes
with cancel-worthy behaviors.
Like Jose Rizal,
who was a womanizer.
Juan Luna was a wife killer.
So... Wilberto could really
have ghosted his sister.
You have a point, bestie.
But I don't think he did it.
I still believe
he didn't mean to leave Nadia.
Because imagine...
Would he put in
this much effort,
talking to random strangers,
just to reach out to her
even after death?
[SMACKS LIPS]
Well, there's only
one way to find out.
I've wasted
so much time, girl.
My issue is nothing
compared to Wilberto's.
Instead of helping
him out immediately,
I prioritized that damned
ex-boyfriend of mine.
Oh, girl, don't invalidate
your feelings.
That's a no-no for me, okay?
You know my feelings on that.
Anyway...
I need your help
with Grandma tomorrow.
- Sure.
- That way...
we could go search
for Nadia tomorrow.
Alright.
I've got you.
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
You sure you don't
need help with that?
I can handle it.
Thanks for letting me stay.
Wait, wait, wait.
Hold on. Hold your horses.
I've changed my mind.
You're not going.
Grandma, that will make it
harder for us to leave.
That's why I'm doing it.
Our bonding time is too short.
It's still your
vacation, Janine.
Why are you
in a rush to leave?
- [GIRLS STUTTER]
- [MALOU] Oh...
Don't tell me it's because
of your ex-boyfriend again.
Wha-- Grandma, no!
- He's an ex. Red flag.
- He's my ex, Grandma.
Um, there's-- There's
something we need to do.
- We have something to do.
- Yes, right.
Also, Grandma,
don't you worry.
If Jaja here does
something stupid,
I'll tell you immediately.
- Hm... Really?
- Yes, of course.
And, Grandma,
like I told you last night,
it will help me
move on faster if I leave.
- [CHUCKLES]
- All right.
Oh, be careful, you two, hm?
- We will. Thank you.
- Yes.
- I'll miss you two.
- Bye, Grandma.
Let's keep
in touch, Grandma.
- Huh?
- Of course.
I have your number saved.
- Stay out of trouble, hm?
- I will.
I'll take care of her.
Don't worry.
Tell me if
she gets into trouble.
- I'll text you immediately.
- Make sure you do.
She knows he's a red flag now.
Could you introduce us
to your grandmother?
- Negative.
- What's negative?
Ah! Right, yeah...
Grandma, it's uh...
Vhal's a negative topic to me.
- That's right, Grandma.
- He's a negative.
Major negative vibes
from him.
Hello, Grandma,
even if you can't see us.
- Hmm...
- What-- What's that?
- Whoo!
- Oh, it's so hot!
Yes, girly pop! It's so hot!
- Come on. Let's go.
- Yeah, let's go.
Grandma, turn on the fan.
It's really hot, okay?
- I will, I will.
- Okay, Grandma. Thanks again.
- Hey, don't forget.
- Yes, I'll text you.
It's usually respectful
to introduce
your friends to your
parents or elders.
If I did that,
she wouldn't let me go at all.
Even if she can't see us,
it's still not right for you
to not introduce us.
That way, she wouldn't
worry as much, right?
She'll freak out that I'm
with a mumu (ghost).
What mumu ?
Who are you talking to?
- Ah! She's talking to me.
- I was talking to Emma.
Girly pop-- I mean...
- [BOTH] Mumu! (Ghostie!)
- We call each other that now.
- Ghostie...
- Ghostie?
Bye, Grandma. Love you!
- I think it's time to go...
- [BOTH] Ghostie!
Let's go, girly pop--
I mean, ghostie! Ghostie.
- Yeah!
- They call themselves that?
That's what we used to call
those long, flowy dresses.
- Hi, ma'am! Back so soon?
- Hi, mister!
We're back with a vengeance!
Oh, how have you been?
We're going to leave
our bags in our room, okay?
Then we'll go
to your sister's house.
Come on, let's go
to the common area.
Ma'am, we aren't allowed
in the common area.
Ah! Yes, yes. Hello?
I'm on the phone with someone.
Yeah, we're going up
to the common area.
Okay. Bye-bye.
All right.
[EMMA] Ah.
Psst! Hey! What are you--
Ah... [AWKWARD CHUCKLE]
Sorry, I didn't mean to...
- You're so beautiful. Sexy.
- She's very pretty.
- Ooh...
- Psst, come on.
[SUITCASE THUDDING]
Why have you been
silent this whole time?
[SUITCASE THUDDING]
We should--
We should introduce
ourselves properly
to my sister later.
[JAJA SNICKERS]
Like we should've done
at your grandmother's earlier.
Oh, for the love of...
You're still stuck on that?
She would've just freaked out.
She might think
I've gone cray-cray.
Oh, you don't know
what cray-cray means, huh?
Cray-cray...
You don't get it?
Like you, from head to toe.
You know, you're lucky that
everyone's on vacation.
Otherwise, people would think
that I'm talking to thin air.
[DESCENDS INTO LAUGHTER,
LAUGHING SILENTLY]
[INHALES LOUDLY]
Me, talking to thin air?
- [LAUGHING SILENTLY]
- [SLAPS SUITCASE HANDLE]
[LAUGHING SILENTLY]
I'm happy to see you smiling.
[SLOW GASP]
["KINAKABAHAN" BY LILY
PLAYING]
Thank you.
And thanks
for the distraction.
[EMMA CLEARS HER THROAT]
Ma'am... Could I also
distract you for a bit?
Bestie, I didn't
see you there!
- Bestie!
- You didn't say anything!
- I've been waiting for you!
- Oh, really now?
- You forgot about me, hm?
- Uh, we'll go upstairs, okay?
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Maybe you'd like
to stay longer?
- You know, for...
- [TONY] Hey... Why?
"LADIES ONLY"
The other babes
can't see us, dude.
We shouldn't miss this chance.
Yuck! You're such a pervert.
You know Tonyo,
if you were still alive,
you would've been
cancelled long ago.
Especially with how rampant
cancel culture is nowadays.
[EMMA SCOFFS]
"Cancer?"
That's an illness, right?
I'm already dead.
How would I get cancer?
[DOOR OPENING]
- Unbelievable.
- I really need to pee, girl.
Yeah, go ahead.
[JAJA SIGHS]
- [STUFF THUDDING]
- [JAJA SNICKERING]
[FRIDGE DOOR SQUEAKING]
So stupid...
Still... Why does he
need to be like that?
Puh-lease. [CHUCKLES]
Wow, that's a pretty
bright smile, bestie.
You know, I've noticed that
you're getting really
comfortable around Wilberto.
- Huh?
- [TEASING] Huh?
You laugh when
you're with him.
You feel shy...
And what was that
secret smile earlier?
Is that how it is
having a third eye?
You notice so many things.
Girl, come on.
Is there something going on?
- Is that what you're seeing?
- Why do you think I'm asking?
Oh, jeez. It's nothing.
I just see him
a bit differently
after learning about his past.
Girl, do you think
I'm going to waste time
thinking about my
worthless ex-boyfriend
when a literal ghost is
dealing with a bigger issue?
[CLICKS TONGUE] Well, I'm just
making sure, bestie, that...
You know...
Oh, forget about it.
Just guard your heart, okay?
"Guard your heart?"
[CHAIR SCRAPING]
You're overreacting.
Oh, wow. I'm the one
overreacting, huh?
- Excuse me.
- Mm?
Girl, may I remind you
that Treb is a ghost.
- And so?
- Also...
Why would I fall
in love with a ghost?
Well, I'm just saying,
bestie, okay?
You know, if it's love...
[BOTH] Mmm!
Imagine this.
You two, crossing heaven
and earth just to be together.
Girl, remember this.
A fragile heart
doesn't get to choose
when to fall in love.
- Wow!
- Am I right?
That's pretty poetic!
[GIGGLES] I think
Treb has rubbed off on me!
- But, girl...
- Hmm?
- Thanks for the concern.
- Of course.
Right now,
I just really want to help him.
[CLICKS TONGUE] After all
the help I got from Wilberto...
You know...
I'd be fine if he gets a
storybook ending instead of me.
I just want him
to make up with his sister.
Whoa, you talk
like a girl in love.
Hmm, so which ghost
should I pick?
- Seriously?!
- [LAUGHS]
Okay, that's enough.
Treb is waiting for us.
Well, you sound giddy.
Alright, let's hurry, then.
[SQUEALS]
[SIGHS NERVOUSLY]
Chill out, dude.
They'll be here any minute.
- [EMMA] You ready?
- [JAJA] Come on, bestie.
Shall we go?
- Come on.
- Let's go.
Aw, shucks! I forgot my
healing oil. I'll go get it.
- I'm coming with you! Hey!
- [JAJA] Hurry up.
Hey, if you want to come,
then get moving!
[TONY] I want to see the view.
[EMMA] You better make sure
that's all you look at.
[ELEVATOR DINGS,
ELEVATOR DOOR CLOSES]
Hey...
[WILBERTO BREATHING NERVOUSLY]
[SOFT MUSIC PLAYING]
Relax!
Touching a man
is not very ladylike.
Well, excuse me, boomer!
Don't get so full of yourself.
I just wanted to calm you down.
- Hmph! Overreact much?
- [CLAPS]
You think I'm hitting on you?
And I wasn't stepping
on you or anything.
Jeez, I was just trying
to calm you down.
[QUIRKY MUSIC PLAYING]
[SIGHS]
Okay, then...
Just lay your palm out
like this.
Go ahead.
["MULTO" BY HEALY AFTER
DARK PLAYING]
["MULTO" CONTINUES]
Do you feel cold?
Huh?
Or maybe it's because
you're dead.
[STIFLED LAUGH]
Well, I am.
You're way too serious!
I'm worried my sister
will get upset at me again.
Oh, come on!
[SLAPS]
Leave it to me.
Jaja got you.
How would you assist me?
What if...
we bring her something
to ease the tension?
"Ease the..."
Is that what women
are into these days?
You should have
a little more self-respect.
Huh?!
Ease the tension...
By giving a souvenir,
an offering, or simply a gift!
- So, what would she like?
- Oh, a gift.
I don't know.
I haven't seen her
in a long time.
Oh, please.
There must be something.
A gift...
Oh, I know!
[BRIGHT MUSIC PLAYING]
Hey, let me know
if someone's coming.
Why not just purchase them
in a store?
What, you got the cash
for it?
See? Exactly.
Besides, nobody sells
Kerson fruits in the market.
Hey!
You pervert!
[WILBERTO GRUNTING]
[JAJA] Hey!
- I'll take care of him!
- You sure?
- Are you talking to me?
- Yeah, you pervert!
You think I wouldn't see you
looking up my skirt?
Pervert!
Ma'am, I was looking up
at the tree.
Then what's this?
Give me that!
You think you're tough?
I have no problem
hitting women, you know!
You talk too much!
Dodge! Block! Use your knee!
Hit his head! Good!
[MAN GROANING]
- Enough! Stop!
- That's it!
[MAN GROANING]
- I've had enough!
- You jerk!
This girl is a lunatic!
You forgot your phone!
- You want to fight, too?
- What? No!
Who else wants some?!
[QUIRKY MUSIC PLAYING]
[SCOFFS]
What about you?
You fight like the female
revolutionaries of old.
It's beguiling.
Hey...
I've done my research.
I know what beguiling means.
You're good.
Whoo, psyche!
How about a salute, then?
A salute?
Then do it like this. Bam!
And then, bam!
There. From now on,
that's how you'll do it.
Like this.
[PHONE RINGING]
[EMMA] Hey, girl!
Where are you?
We're picking Kerson fruits
for Grandma.
And guess what.
A pervert came by.
He was looking up my skirt!
So then, I gave him
a good thrashing!
Girly Pop, you're the epitome
of "small but terrible."
But I'm glad he didn't try
to get back at you.
So there are more perverts
in this day and age.
Good thing you got some
boxing skills, chica!
My mother told me
to train myself.
She said, as an only girl,
I should be able
to defend myself.
- But you know what, bestie?
- Hmm?
Isn't it great to have
a knight in shining armor, too?
- You feel like a princess!
- What did she say?
She said you saved her
from the pervert.
- You're slow.
- I wanted to defend you,
but I couldn't do anything.
I apologize, Jaja.
Hey, I'm just kidding.
But you did try your best,
so thank you.
Also, no one has ever
done that for me before.
You're the first.
So thank you so much
for the effort.
If I was alive, I would've
done it again and again.
[JAJA GIGGLES]
Emma, we're here.
[EMMA] Is this it?
[SOFT MUSIC PLAYING]
Girl!
[HISSES] Hey!
Are you just going
to stare at each other,
or are we still
visiting Nadia?
- I apologize.
- You're going past it, man!
- Girly Pop!
- We're here. Come on.
Get over here.
I got a question for you.
Girl, what was that?
Now, you're exchanging glances
with each other?
Are you a dictionary?
You put meaning into everything.
I was just thanking him
for his efforts.
- Come on.
- Okay. If you say so.
[WILBERTO] We're here.
[EMMA] Oh.
Wow! A lion? Seriously?
- [CLAPS]
- So awesome!
This is it.
We have the option
to open her third eye.
I've got my healing oil.
I've given it
consideration, Emma.
It's certainly the
most efficient way,
but my sister wouldn't
desire it.
She tends to mistrust people.
It's also possible that
she may not want to see me.
Oh, come on!
Don't worry!
Emma, plus Jaja,
at your service.
Think of it like a game.
Pass the Message.
Now, let's go.
[KNOCKING]
[QUIRKY MUSIC PLAYING]
Hello, sir. I'm Jaja.
And this is my friend...
- Emma.
Sorry. Not interested
in your offer.
- It's not a pyramid scheme!
- We're not selling anything!
- Look. Here's my ID.
- Here.
[JAJA]
Tourism student, Dean's Lister,
influencer with 10K followers.
[CHUCKLES] Perfect.
Um... We just want
to see Nadia--
I mean, Grandma Nadia.
It's for Wilberto's sake.
Let me guess.
You have a third eye,
and you're with
Grandpa Wilberto right now.
- Correct!
- That's right!
[EMMA] No, hold on--
[JAJA] Wait!
[GROANS]
Are you okay, ma'am?
["PRINSESA" BY KENANIAH PLAYING]
Does this mean
we're a thing now?
["PRINSESA" CONTINUES]
Why are you so invested?
What's in it for you?
Excuse me?
Are you getting paid? You're
getting paid, aren't you?
Wow.
Are you even thinking?
How would a ghost pay us?
Nadia! Nadia!
- Oh my gosh!
- It's Treb!
Please get out.
If anything happens to Grandma,
you'll be held responsible.
It just hurts that I can't
even talk to her or hold her.
Well-- Well, you could...
But only evil spirits
can do that.
Treb?
How's your sister?
Jaja, I'm useless.
I'm useless.
I'm so useless!